Register to The E. Robert Schmitz Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Financial and Legal Material, 1917-1950; Series VIII; .4' (1 box)
  - Financial Items, VIII.A
    - Financial record by season, 1 item; [26] sheets; 31 cm. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Includes columns for activity, place, date, fee, manager, and percent to manager
    - Crédit Lyonnais, 30 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Includes statements, receipts, and correspondence
    - A. Durand & Fils Éditeurs, 9 items. (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Includes receipts and expense statements
    - Federal individual income tax material for E. Robert Schmitz, 1922-1943; 68 items. (Box 22, Folder 4-6)
      Includes correspondence, receipts, and returns
      See also: VII. A.3. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER MUSIC SCHOOLS. Trust fund
    - Canadian income tax, 1941-1950; 67 items. (Box 22, Folder 7-8)
    - Box office statements for concert halls, 1920-1938; 19 items. (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous financial items, 85 items. (Box 22, Folder 10)
      Includes royalty statement, payment stubs, receipts, correspondence, and bills for hotel, post office, printers, telephone, and insurance, and chattel mortgage
  - Legal Items, VIII.B
    - Sheet with history of military service for Camille Schmitz, 1917-1918; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - House lease, 1932 Aug.; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Lowry Field Certificate of Service, 1944 Dec.; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Notice of hearing for letters of administration for the estate of E. Robert Schmitz, 1949 Sep.; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Scrapbooks, 1919-1949; Series IX; 2.5' (6 boxes)
  This series includes the microfilm and copyflo copy of eight scrapbooks. The scrapbooks contained clippings, correspondence, photographs, programs, and publicity material. The scrapbooks were microfilmed and a reading copy on copyflo was made before the scrapbooks were disassembled. Many of the items were removed at the Yale Library's Conservation Studio. Items other than clippings were then filed with the appropriate series, and a pencil note was made on each item stating which scrapbook it was originally in.
  There is also a scrapbook containing information about Pro-Musica and its activities. The loose items were copied onto acid-free paper, and the original programs, publicity material, and correspondence, were filed in the appropriate series.
  - Scrapbook containing information about Pro-Musica and its activities, 1911-1934 (Box 23)
  - Microfilm of 8 scrapbooks on 5 reels, 1919-1949 (Box 23)
  - Copyflo of 5 reels of microfilm of 8 scrapbooks, 1919-1949 (Box 24–28)